So now we're going to start on the ear, take a bit of oil and your brush, fill in, so I'm just going to put this on the ear.
Final black and brown, then just underneath the ear.
A bit more red in there, burnt umber.
Use some burnt umber, maybe a touch of black, put this bit of shadow in here.
Use a bit of a light shape, bring it through that.
Maybe add a touch of orange.
Make those shadows.
Now we can look in the ear and be using burnt umber.
And it's like a bit more on the red side.
Put this in.
That's something solid colours will start working with.
Then we can go lighter.
So some orange burnt umber.
The side of the ear, that seems to orange.
Maybe add a touch of violet in there.
Give me the red.
Just bring in the shape back.
The helix, that lighter edge.
Orange, orange.
Put this shape in here.
We're out of this there.
We've got this little cast shadow from the hair.
Put this in.
There's a bit of light being caught on the ear.
Call that some alizarin.
Just tone that down with some green.
And a bit of yellow.
Check in there.
Just darken that along the edges.
Check in that form to turn.
Okay, then going on with the ear.
Yellow.
Insignia tragus.
Slightly darker in there.
Maybe some orange just to pull this light shape out of the ear.
Maybe get it a bit darker.
Around that edge.
Just along this edge here.
More red.
Some red.
More on the red side.
Around the edge of the ear.
More red.
Then just looking at these shadows.
This comes into a bit of shadow around here.
Probably some burnt umber.
A bit of mid violet maybe.
Mid to dark violet.
Purple.
A touch of yellow in there.
A bit darker.
A bit warmer.
A touch of red.
A bit of burnt umber.
Roughly along this edge here.
And soften that.
And the shadow gets a bit lighter.
Add some orange.
Same for this shape here.
Lighter.
Okay.
Shape of the tragus.
The overall tone.
And this one.
Some violets in there.
A bit darker maybe.
A bit more yellow in there.
A bit more violet on that edge.
Okay.
I'm just going to put the whole shape in.
I'm going to pick out the lights on this edge.
To the shadow.
Soften that edge.
I'm going to pick out these lights.
A bit of yellowish.
A touch of green just to tone that down a bit.
A touch of red.
A bit darker.
Looks a bit too high contrast.
Okay, so.
We're going to start to look into the
lights.
Around the
shape there.
Let's say
the middle is in.
A touch of burnt umber.
And in there.
Then here starts the turn.
The middle is in orange.
And we've got the shape inside the tragus.
I'm going to put this darker shape in.
Then pick out the lighter shape.
Kind of a lizzard.
Okay. Darker again.
A touch of green.
So I'm just picking out this shape inside
the conch.
I'm going to pick out this.
A shadow there.
Looks like a
orange.
A slightly cooler.
So orange purple.
Just along that edge there.
A little lighter.
That orange lizzard.
A bit darker.
The edge of that.
A darker shape there a bit.
O.K.
Just looking inside the conch.
Shape
inside of the ear.
Just put this shape in here.
Like a
yellowish lizzard.
The green is slightly darker in there.
icishy yellow.
more on this one okay get slightly redder between the the helix and the
Hunter helix just bring in this shadow back here and then we've got the just a
bit darker orange so some illiterate just picking out these little micro
planes okay pick out the highlights light inside the ear and just picking
out some of these lights and these cakes a bit more subtle bit too much contrast in
places just with the hair a few strands of hair coming over the ear
pick those out lighter strands gonna use a bit of orange burnt amber okay that's the ear